BiblioTech Connections: Newsletter of the Tisch Library UP078
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
BiblioTech Connections: Newsletter of the Tisch Library
1993 -- 2008
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tisch Library
UP078
0.25 Linear Feet
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains issues of BiblioTech Connections. It was a newsletter published by the Tisch Library. It was distributed to faculty and staff and includes news about the library's programs, events and acquisitions. BiblioTech Connections began publication in Fall 1993 and it descended from the previous Tisch Library Newsletter, Jumbo's Tale. It completed publication in Fall 2008, and was succeeded by the TischLibrary Connections in Fall 2009. From Fall 1993 through Spring 2007, BiblioTech Connections was published three times a year: Fall, Winter, and Spring. Starting in the Fall of 2007, publication decreased to twice a year: Fall and Spring.
Related Materials
UP234, Jumbo's Tale, newsletter of the Arts and Sciences library, DCA
UP258, TischLibrary Connections, DCA
UP232, Tufts University Library Newsletter, DCA
Biographical / Historical
The Tisch Library (1860-present) opened in 1996 as the main Arts, Sciences, and Engineering library at Tufts University, made possible by a generous donation from the Tisch family. Between 1965 and 1996, the Arts and Sciences library was known as the Wessell Library. From 1908-1965, the library was known as the Eaton Library and was housed in Eaton Hall.
Prior to the 1860-1861 school year, the library began as the personal collection of President Hosea Ballou. In 1860, that collection was moved to Ballou Hall as a permanent library space for students to have easier access to the material. In 1886, the library moved to Middle Hall (later called Packard Hall) (Light on the Hill, 74). In 1906, Andrew Carnegie donated $100,000 to build the Eaton Library, in its own space. The Eaton Library, completed in 1908, was named after Crane Theological School graduate Rev. Charles H. Eaton, who was the Carnegie family pastor who graduated in 1874 (Light on the Hill, 201).
In 1965, the entire collection of the Eaton Library moved into a brand-new building, the Wessell Library, named for Tufts University President Nils Y. Wessell. The collection comprised of Crane Theological School materials temporarily moved into the Wessell Library in the mid-1960s, but the materials were transferred to the Harvard Divinity School in 1973 after the Crane Theological School closed in 1968.
The Wessell Library, which then became the main library for Arts, Sciences, and Engineering (the latter department moved its collection to Wessell Library in 1990 from the Lufkin Engineering Library). In 1996, the name of the library was changed to the Tisch Library after a donation from the Tisch family (Jonathan Tisch is an alumnus and is on the Board of Trustees). The library currently houses the collection for the Arts, Sciences, and Engineering departments.
- BiblioTech Connections: Newsletter of the Tisch Library, 1993 -- 2008; UP078.001; 0.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains issues of BiblioTech Connections.It was a newsletter published by the Tisch Library. It was distributed to faculty and staff and includes news about the library's programs, events and acquisitions. BiblioTech Connections began publication in Fall 1993 and it descended from the previous Tisch Library Newsletter, Jumbo's Tale. From Fall 1993 through Spring 2007, it was published three times a year: Fall, Winter, and Spring. Starting in the Fall of 2007, publication decreased to twice a year: Fall and Spring. The last issue was published in Fall 2008. It was succeeded by the TischLibrary Connections.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 8, Fall, 1993; UP078.001.001.00001 (Box Shared 7)
    This publication starts with issue number 8. It follows the previous Tisch Library Newsletter "Jumbo's Tale".
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 9, Winter, 1994; UP078.001.001.00002 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 10, Spring, 1999; UP078.001.001.00003 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 11, Fall, 1994; UP078.001.001.00004 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 12, Winter, 1995; UP078.001.001.00005 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 13, Spring, 1995; UP078.001.001.00006 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 14, Fall, 1995; UP078.001.001.00007 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 15, Winter, 1996; UP078.001.001.00008 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 16, Spring, 1996; UP078.001.001.00009 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 17, Fall, 1996; UP078.001.001.00010 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 18, Winter, 1997; UP078.001.001.00011 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 19, Spring, 1997; UP078.001.001.00012 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 20, Fall, 1997; UP078.001.001.00013 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 20 [21], Winter, 1998; UP078.001.001.00014 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 22, Spring, 1998; UP078.001.001.00015 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 23, Fall, 1998; UP078.001.001.00016 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 24, Winter, 1999; UP078.001.001.00017 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 25, Spring, 1999; UP078.001.001.00018 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 26, Fall, 1999; UP078.001.001.00019 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 27, Winter, 2000; UP078.001.001.00020 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 28, Spring, 2000; UP078.001.001.00021 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 29, Fall, 2000; UP078.001.001.00022 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 30, Winter, 2001; UP078.001.001.00023 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 31, Spring, 2001; UP078.001.001.00024 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 32, Fall, 2001; UP078.001.001.00025 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 33, Winter, 2002; UP078.001.001.00026 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 34, Spring, 2002; UP078.001.001.00027 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 35, Fall, 2002; UP078.001.001.00028 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 36, Winter, 2003; UP078.001.001.00029 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 37, Spring, 2003; UP078.001.001.00030 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 38, Fall, 2003; UP078.001.001.00031 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 39, Winter, 2004; UP078.001.001.00032 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 40, Spring, 2004; UP078.001.001.00033 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 41, Fall, 2004; UP078.001.001.00034 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 42, Winter, 2005; UP078.001.001.00035 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 43, Spring, 2005; UP078.001.001.00036 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 44, Fall, 2005; UP078.001.001.00037 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 45, Winter, 2006; UP078.001.001.00038 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 46, Spring, 2006; UP078.001.001.00039 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 47, Fall, 2006; UP078.001.001.00040 (Box Shared 7)
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 48, Spring, 2007; UP078.001.001.00041 (Box Shared 7)
    Issue
    48
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 49, Fall, 2007; UP078.001.001.00042 (Box Shared 7)
    As of this publication, BiblioTech Connections is published twice a year, in the Fall and in the Spring.
  - BiblioTech Connections, Number 50, Spring, 2008; UP078.001.001.00043 (Box Shared 7)